A Guide to the J. Hoge Tyler Family Collection, 1802-1956
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Clark, Champ, The Philippine problem (Washington, D.C.: [Government Printing Office], 1900).
Goodwin, W. P., Experience of an old soldier in the Army of Northern Virginia, 1862 to 1865 (Bowling Green, VA: Echo Printing, 1907).
Gray, Horace, An Address on the life character and influence of Chief Justice Marshall (Washington, D.C.: Pearson Printing Office, 1901).
Haggard, H. Rider, King Solomon's mines (New York: F. M. Lupton, [19--?]).
Jamestown Official Photograph Corporation, The Jamestown Exposition illustrated (New York: Press of I. H. Blanchard Co., 1907).
John Warwick Daniel, late a senator from Virginia: memorial addresses delivered in the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States (Washington: U.S. G.P.O., 1911).
Johnston, Mattie Reed, Six prayers; or, the soul's reflector (Richmond, VA: Whittet & Shepperson, 1899).
Mann, William Hodges, Proclamation by the Governor of Virginia, 1910.
McBride, J. F., The Higher officials of the United States and buildings where all laws are made (Chicago: J. F. McBride & Co., 1894).
Memorial addresses on the life and character of William H. F. Lee (a representative from Virginia) delivered in the House of Representatives and in the Senate ... (Washington: Government Printing Office, 1892).
Military show: program and guide to exhibits ([Fort Snelling, MN: Fort Snelling, 1928]).
Official Army Register for 1899 (Washington: Adjutant General's Office, 1899).
People and Politics ([Roanoke, VA: Stone Printing and Manufacturing, 19--?]).
Settlement of the debt of the state of Virginia: under the bondholders' agreement of May 12, 1890 ... ([New York: Bondholders' Committee, 1892]).
Smith, Orlando, The Agreement between science and religion (New York: C. P. Farrell, [c1906]).
Society of the Army of the Potomac, Proceedings of the thirty-first annual reunion, held at Fredericksburg, May 25th & 26th, 1900 (New York: McGowan & Slipper, 1900).
Southworth, Emma D. E. N. Sybil Brotherton (New York: F. M. Lupton, [19--?]).
Thomas Staples Martin (late a senator from Virginia): memorial addresses delivered in the Senate and the House of Representatives of the United States... (Washington: Government Printing Office, 1922).
Tyler, James Hoge, The Family of Hoge: a genealogy ([Greensboro, NC]: James Fulton Hoge, 1927).
Virginia: its agricultural and industrial resources ([Richmond: Virginia Dept. of Agriculture and Immigration, 1914]).
Young, Isabel N., The Hawaiian Islands; and, the story of pineapple (New York: Home Economics Dept., American Can Co., [1935]).
The following items were transferred to the Newspapers Collection:
The Alexandria Times (Alexandria, Virginia), May 29, 1897.
Midland Virginian (Palmyra, Virginia), April 7, 1898.
The following item was transferred to the Historical Maps Collection:
A Historical map of Virginia (Richmond, VA: GHQ Committee, Kappa Alpha Order, 1925).
An oil painting of J. Hoge Tyler and his daughter Lily (Eliza Tyler Wilson) is part of this collection. See Art-359. Due to its size, it is housed separately in the art collection.
Contents List
- SERIES I: POLITICAL PAPERS 1859-1923
  - Subseries A: Executive Letter Books 1898-1901
    - Index to executive correspondence 1898-1901
      - A-Z (Box-folder 1-1-9)
    - Incoming correspondence 1898-1901
      - nos. 1-400 (Box-folder 1-10)
      - nos. 401-1200 (Box-folder 2-1-2)
      - nos. 1201-1999 (Box-folder 3-1-2)
      - nos. 2000-2800 (Box-folder 4-1-2)
      - nos. 2801-3600 (Box-folder 5-1-2)
      - nos. 3601-4400 (Box-folder 6-1-2)
      - nos. 4401-5200 (Box-folder 7-1-2)
      - nos. 5201-6000 (Box-folder 8-1-2)
      - nos. 6001-6800 (Box-folder 9-1-2)
      - nos. 6801-7600 (Box-folder 10-1-2)
      - nos. 7601-8400 (Box-folder 11-1-2)
      - nos. 8401-9200 (Box-folder 12-1-2)
    - Incoming / outgoing correspondence 1898-1901
      - nos. 9201-9600 (9201-9216 incoming; 9217-9600 outgoing) (Box-folder 13-1)
      - nos. 9601-10220 (9601-9725 outgoing; 9726-10220 incoming) (Box-folder 13-2)
    - Outgoing correspondence 1898-1901
      - nos. 1-1200 (Box-folder 14-1-3)
      - nos. 1201-2321 (Box-folder 15-1-3)
      - nos. 2322-4099 (Box-folder 16-1-3)
      - nos. 5000-14099 (Box-folder 17-1-3)
      - nos. 15000-18040 (Box-folder 18-1)
  - Subseries B: Subject Files 1897-1901
    - Appointments
      - College of William and Mary 1897-1898 (Box-folder 18-2)
      - Flour inspector (Alexandria) 1898 (Box-folder 18-3)
      - Governor's staff (correspondents A-F) 1897 (Box-folder 18-4)
      - Governor's staff (correspondents G-M) 1897 (Box-folder 18-5)
      - Governor's staff (correspondents N-R) 1897 (Box-folder 18-6)
      - Governor's staff (correspondents S-Z) 1897 (Box-folder 18-7)
      - Judge, Elizabeth City and Warwick counties 1901 (Box-folder 18-8)
      - Judge, Fluvanna County 1897-1898, n.d. (Box-folder 18-9-11)
      - Judge, Henry County 1900 (Box-folder 18-12)
      - Judge, 3rd Judicial Circuit 1898 (Box-folder 19-1-8)
      - Judge, 13th Judicial Circuit 1898 (Box-folder 19-9)
      - Judge, 17th Judicial Circuit Aug-Sep 1899, n.d. (Box-folder 19-10-11)
      - Labor commissioner (James B. Doherty) 1899 (Box-folder 19-12)
      - Labor commissioner (W. L. Eckles) 1899 (Box-folder 19-13)
      - Labor commissioner (George O. Green) 1899 (Box-folder 19-14)
      - Labor commissioner (Leonard Knapp) 1899 (Box-folder 19-15)
      - Labor commissioner (William H. Mullen) 1899 (Box-folder 19-16)
      - Labor commissioner (Robert R. Nuckols) 1898 (Box-folder 19-17)
      - Labor commissioner (other applicants) 1899 (Box-folder 19-18)
      - Quarantine officer (Newport News) 1898-1899 (Box-folder 20-1-4)
      - Quarantine officer (Norfolk) 1897-1900, n.d. (Box-folder 20-5-12)
      - School superintendents (localities A-C) 1899-1901 (Box-folder 20-13-17)
      - School superintendents (localities D-Z) 1899-1901 (Box-folder 21-1-14)
      - State hospital board (Central) 1897-1899 (Box-folder 21-15)
      - State hospital board (Eastern) 1897-1901 (Box-folder 21-16)
      - State hospital board (Southwestern) 1897-1899 (Box-folder 22-1-5)
      - State hospital board (Western) 1897-1901 (Box-folder 22-6)
      - State penitentiary board 1897-1898 (Box-folder 22-7)
      - State penitentiary physician 1897-1900 (Box-folder 22-8-9)
      - State penitentiary staff 1897-1899 (Box-folder 22-10)
      - University of Virginia board of visitors 1897-1901 (Box-folder 22-11)
      - Virginia Military Institute board of visitors 1897-1900 (Box-folder 22-12)
      - Virginia Polytechnic Institute board of visitors 1897-1900 (Box-folder 22-13)
      - Virginia School for the Deaf and the Blind 1898-1899 (Box-folder 22-14)
      - Virginia Supreme Court Aug-Dec 1900 (Box-folder 22-15-18)
      - Virginia Volunteer Infantry Aug-Dec 1898, n.d. (Box-folder 23-1-4)
      - Miscellaneous and unspecified positions 1897-1901, n.d. (Box-folder 23-5-6)
    - Congratulatory letters
      - Correspondents A-C (Box-folder 23-7)
      - Correspondents D-K (Box-folder 23-8)
      - Correspondents L-N (Box-folder 23-9)
      - Correspondents O-R (Box-folder 23-10)
      - Correspondents S-Z (Box-folder 23-11)
    - Contingency fund 1898-1901, n.d. (Box-folder 23-12-18)
    - Debt settlement 1890, n.d. (Box-folder 24-1)
    - Oyster beds 1900-1901 (Box-folder 24-2)
    - Rosslyn, Virginia charter 1896-1898, n.d. (Box-folder 24-3-4)
    - Schoolbook controversy 1898, n.d. (Box-folder 24-5)
    - Staples, Martin extradition 1900-1901 (Box-folder 24-6)
    - State hospitals 1898-1901, n.d. (Box-folder 24-7)
    - State penitentiary 1898 (Box-folder 24-8)
    - Virginia Military Institute 1899-1901 (Box-folder 24-9)
    - Virginia School for the Deaf and the Blind 1899 (Box-folder 24-10)
    - Virginia-Tennessee border controversy 1899 (Box-folder 24-11)
    - Virginia Volunteer Infantry 1898-1901, n.d. (Box-folder 24-12-17)
  - Subseries C: Gubernatorial Campaign Canvass 1897
    - Accomack County (Box-folder 24-18)
    - Albemarle County, [2 folders] (Box-folder 24-19)
    - Alexandria County (Box-folder 25-1)
    - Alleghany and Amelia counties (Box-folder 25-2)
    - Amherst and Appomattox counties (Box-folder 25-3)
    - Augusta County (Box-folder 25-4)
    - Bath, Bedford and Bland counties (Box-folder 25-5)
    - Botetourt County (Box-folder 25-6)
    - Brunswick County (Box-folder 25-7)
    - Buchanan and Buckingham counties (Box-folder 25-8)
    - Campbell County, [2 folders] (Box-folder 25-9)
    - Caroline, Carroll and Charles City counties (Box-folder 25-10)
    - Charlotte County (Box-folder 25-11)
    - Chesterfield and Clarke counties (Box-folder 25-12)
    - Craig, Culpeper and Cumberland counties (Box-folder 23-13)
    - Dickenson County (Box-folder 25-14)
    - Dinwiddie County (Box-folder 25-15)
    - Elizabeth City and Essex counties (Box-folder 26-1)
    - Fairfax and Fauquier counties (Box-folder 26-2)
    - Floyd, Fluvanna and Franklin counties (Box-folder 26-3)
    - Frederick County (Box-folder 26-4)
    - Giles, Gloucester and Goochland counties (Box-folder 26-5)
    - Grayson and Greene counties (Box-folder 26-6)
    - Greensville County (Box-folder 26-7)
    - Halifax and Hanover counties (Box-folder 26-8)
    - Henrico County (Box-folder 26-9)
    - Henry and Highland counties (Box-folder 26-10)
    - Isle of Wight, James City, King and Queen, King George and King William counties (Box-folder 26-11)
    - Lancaster and Loudoun counties (Box-folder 26-12)
    - Louisa and Lunenburg counties (Box-folder 26-13)
    - Madison and Mathews counties (Box-folder 26-14)
    - Mecklenburg, Middlesex and Montgomery counties (Box-folder 26-15)
    - Nansemond, Nelson and New Kent counties (Box-folder 27-1)
    - Newport News (Box-folder 27-2)
    - Norfolk County, [2 folders] (Box-folder 27-3)
    - Northampton, Northumberland and Nottaway counties (Box-folder 27-4)
    - Orange County (Box-folder 27-5)
    - Page and Patrick counties (Box-folder 27-6)
    - Pittsylvania County, [2 folders] (Box-folder 27-7)
    - Powhatan, Prince Edward and Prince George counties (Box-folder 27-8)
    - Prince William, Princess Anne and Pulaski counties (Box-folder 27-9)
    - Rappahannock County (Box-folder 27-10)
    - Richmond, [see also Box 28, Folder 1] (Box-folder 27-11)
    - Richmond, [see also Box 27, Folder 11] (Box-folder 28-1)
    - Richmond County (Box-folder 28-2)
    - Roanoke County (Box-folder 28-3)
    - Rockbridge County (Box-folder 28-4)
    - Rockingham and Russell counties (Box-folder 28-5)
    - Scott and Shenandoah counties (Box-folder 28-6)
    - Smyth and Southampton counties (Box-folder 28-7)
    - Spotsylvania and Stafford counties (Box-folder 28-8)
    - Surry and Sussex counties (Box-folder 28-9)
    - Tazewell County (Box-folder 28-10)
    - Warren and Warwick counties (Box-folder 28-11)
    - Washington and Westmoreland counties (Box-folder 28-12)
    - Wise and Wythe counties (Box-folder 28-13)
    - York County (Box-folder 28-14)
  - Subseries D: Senatorial Campaign Canvass 1899
    - Accomack and Albemarle counties (Box-folder 28-15)
    - Alexandria, Alleghany, Amelia, Amherst, Appomattox and Augusta counties (Box-folder 29-1)
    - Bath, Bedford and Bland counties (Box-folder 29-2)
    - Botetourt, Brunswick, Buchanan and Buckingham counties (Box-folder 29-3)
    - Campbell, Caroline and Carroll counties (Box-folder 29-4)
    - Charlotte, Chesterfield and Clarke counties (Box-folder 29-5)
    - Craig, Culpeper and Cumberland counties (Box-folder 29-6)
    - Dickenson, Dinwiddie, Elizabeth City and Essex counties (Box-folder 29-7)
    - Fairfax, Fauquier, Floyd, Fluvanna and Frederick counties (Box-folder 29-8)
    - Giles, Gloucester, Goochland, Grayson, Greene and Greensville counties (Box-folder 29-9)
    - Halifax County (Box-folder 29-10)
    - Hanover, Henry and Highland counties (Box-folder 29-11)
    - Isle of Wight, King George and King William counties (Box-folder 29-12)
    - Lancaster, Lee, Loudoun, Louisa and Lunenburg counties (Box-folder 29-13)
    - Madison, Mathews and Mecklenburg counties (Box-folder 29-14)
    - Middlesex and Montgomery counties (Box-folder 29-15)
    - Nelson and New Kent counties (Box-folder 29-16)
    - Norfolk (Box-folder 29-17)
    - Northampton, Northumberland and Nottaway counties (Box-folder 29-18)
    - Orange County (Box-folder 29-19)
    - Patrick County (Box-folder 29-20)
    - Pittsylvania County (Box-folder 30-1)
    - Powhatan, Prince Edward, Prince George, Prince William, Princess Anne and Pulaski counties (Box-folder 30-2)
    - Rappahannock County (Box-folder 30-3)
    - Richmond (Box-folder 30-4)
    - Richmond County (Box-folder 30-5)
    - Roanoke County (Box-folder 30-6)
    - Rockbridge, Rockingham and Russell counties (Box-folder 30-7)
    - Scott and Shenandoah counties (Box-folder 30-8)
    - Smyth, Southampton and Spotsylvania counties (Box-folder 30-9)
    - Stafford, Surry and Sussex counties (Box-folder 30-10)
    - Tazewell County (Box-folder 30-11)
    - Warren and Warwick counties (Box-folder 30-12)
    - Washington County (Box-folder 30-13)
    - Westmoreland, Wise and Wythe counties (Box-folder 30-14)
  - Subseries E: General Political Correspondence 1870-1923
    - 1870-1888 (Box-folder 30-15-18)
    - 1889-Sep 1892 (Box-folder 31-1-15)
    - Oct 1892-Jun 10 1893 (Box-folder 32-1-15)
    - Jun 11 1893-Aug 5 1893 (Box-folder 33-1-14)
    - Aug 6 1893-Dec 1899 (Box-folder 34-1-16)
    - 1900-1912 (Box-folder 35-1-18)
    - 1913-1923, n.d. (Box-folder 36-1-11)
  - Subseries F: Speeches 1877-1907
    - Speech drafts and background materials 1877-1907 (Box-folder 36-12)
    - Speech drafts and background materials n.d., [3 folders; see also Box 37, Folder 1] (Box-folder 36-13)
    - Speech drafts and background materials n.d., [2 folders; see also Box 36, Folder 13] (Box-folder 37-1)
  - Subseries G: Printed Materials 1874-1922
    - A (Box-folder 37-2)
      - "Address of the State Conservative Committee to the people of Virginia" 1876
      - "Annual message of the governor of the state of New York" [1875]
      - Annual report of the treasurer of Virginia for the fiscal year 1891
    - B (Box-folder 37-3)
      - Bailey, J. E., "Payment of government bonds: speech... in the Senate of the United States" 1878
      - "The Barbour Thompson letters raise a moral issue" 1911
      - "Before the Virginia State Board of Education: in the matter of the selection of text books for use in the public free schools of Virginia, and the award of contracts to publishers for furnishing the same for the four years..." 1898
      - "A Bill to empower and instruct the Board of Sinking Fund Commissioners to sell the state's interest in the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad..." [1900?]
      - "A Bill to incorporate the Richmond and Washington Air Line Railway Company" [1900?]
    - C-G (Box-folder 37-4)
      - Clapp, J. W., "Speech... in reference to questions pending before the Senate" [1879]
      - "Communication from the governor in relation to assessment of railroads..." [1900]
      - "Communication from the governor of Virginia transmitting list of pardons, commutations, etc., and reasons therefor" [1901]
      - "Communication from the second auditor in response to a resloution of the House of Delegates asking for information in regard to the effect of the Wickham Amendment..." [1890]
      - "Constitution: qualification of voters" n.d.
      - "Darst, E. L. "Facts about the bond issue" [1922]
      - Dawes, H. L., "Republican testimony as to the extravagance of public expenditures: speech... delivered in the House of Representatives" [1879]
    - H (Box-folder 37-5)
      - "Hand book for Hon. William A. James and Carter Glass, addressed to the Democratic voters in the primary... [1911], [2 copies]
      - Hill, John F., "Inaugural address of John F. Hill to the legislature of the state of Maine..." 1901
      - Hooker, Chas. E., "Political condition of the South: speech... in reply to Hon. G. F. Hoar of Massachusetts, delivered in the United States House of Representatives..." [1876]
      - House, John F., "North and South: the past belongs to history--the future, to us and our children: speech in the United States House of Representatives" 1876
      - Hunton, Eppa and J. Proctor Knott, "Speeches... in reply to the personal explanation of James G. Blaine, delivered in the United States House of Representatives..." [1876]
    - I-L (Box-folder 37-6)
      - "Inauguration of the Jackson statue" [1875]
      - "Is Virginia bankrupt?" [1875?]
      - Johnston, John W., "Coinage of silver dollars: speech... in the Senate of the United States..." 1878
      - Keezel, Geo. B., "How Virginia made and is paying her state debt [1921?]
      - Kemper, James L., "Inaugural address of James L. Kemper, governor of Virginia, to the General Assembly" 1874
      - Lamar, L. Q. C., "Payment of government bonds: speech... in the Senate of the United States..." 1878
      - "List of judges, treasurers, sheriffs and other officers in the state of Virginia 1891
    - M (Box-folder 37-7)
      - Manual of members, officers, and standing committees and rules of the Senate of Virginia; also the constitution of Virginia, &, & 1887
      - McDonald, Joseph E., "Hamburgh riots: speech... in the senate of the United States..." 1876
      - McKinney, P. W., "Republican campaign document: speech of Hon. P. W. McKinney, Democratic nominee for governor, delivered at Charlottesville..." [1889]
      - "A Message from the governor of the commonwealth, inclosing a communication from Mr. John Lubbock, chairman of the Council and Committee of Foreign Bondholders in London" [1889]
      - Morgan, John T., "Radical political morality: tissue ballots in Virginia; the Bourbon Democracy: speech... in the United States Senate..." [1881]
      - Morgan, John T., "Remarks on Negro suffrage, submitted to the members of the Constitutional Convention of Alabama" 1901
      - Morrison, William R., "A Moderate, simple tariff for revenue only: speech... in the House of Representatives..." 1876
    - N-Q (Box-folder 37-8)
      - Owen, Albert Kimsey, The Problems of the hour1897
      - "The People against the bosses: Swanson's confession raises a moral issue" [1911]
      - Pridemore, Auburn L., "Army reorganization--correction of abuses: speech... in the House of Representatives..." 1878
      - Pridemore, Auburn L., "Agriculture, its condition, wrongs, and remedies: speech... in the House of Representatives..." 1879
    - R (Box-folder 37-9)
      - Randall, Samuel J., "The Results of a Democratic House of Representatives, in behalf of retrenchment and reform: speech... in the House of Representatives..." 1876
      - "Reform and better times: facts for independent voters" [1876]
      - "Reform, for president, Samuel J. Tilden; for vice-president, Thomas A. Hendricks: what Tilden has done in breaking rings" [1876]
      - "Reform: Governor Tilden's letter of acceptance" [1876]
      - "Report of the Joint Committee on Revision of the Criminal Laws" [1878]
      - Report of the second auditor on the condition of the public debt of Virginia and of the literary fund, also the report of the commissioners of the sinking fund... 1889
      - Report of the second auditor on the condition of the public debt of Virginia and of the literary fund, also the report of the commissioners of the sinking fund... 1891
      - "The Resignation of William Jennings Bryan as secretary of state..." [1915?]
      - Ruffin, Frank G., "An Examination of Judge Robert W. Hughes decision in the case of John P. Faure vs. the sinking fund of Virginia" 1884
    - S, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 37-10)
      - Saulsbury, Eli, "Coinage of silver dollars: speech... in the Senate of the United States..." 1878
      - "Senator Martin's railroad connections as shown by the Barbour Thompson letters..." [1911], [2 copies]
      - "Special message of the governor of Virginia transmitting report of the commission appointed on the public debt" 1892
      - Statement showing tax imposed on railroad and canal companies in the commonwealth of Virginia... [1891]
      - Statement showing tax imposed on railroad and canal companies in the commonwealth of Virginia... 1899
      - Stenger, W. S., "Freedman's bank: speech: in the United States House of Representatives..." [1876]
    - T-U (Box-folder 37-11)
      - Tebault, C. H., "To the survivors of the Medical Corps of the Army and Navy of the Confederate States" 1898
      - Tucker, J. Randolph, "Contested-election case of Platt vs. Goode" 1876
      - Tyler, J. Hoge, "To encourage mining and manufacturing industries: speech of Sen. J. Hoge Tyler..." 1878, [2 copies]
    - V-Z (Box-folder 37-12)
      - "Virginia debt settlement: official negotiations with opinion of advisory board [1891]
      - Voorhees, D. W., "Credit of the government speech... in the Senate of the United States..." 1878
      - "What happened in the last county election" [1912?]
      - Withers, Robert E. "Coinage of silver dollars: speech... in the Senate of the United States..." 1878
      - Wood, Fernando, "The Resources and expenses of the government: necessity for retrenchment: speech... in the United States House of Representatives..." 1876
    - Newspaper clippings 1876-1915 (Box-folder 37-13-14)
    - Newspaper clippings n.d., [see also Box 38, Folder 1] (Box-folder 37-15)
    - Newspaper clippings n.d., [see also Box 37, Folder 15] (Box-folder 38-1)
    - Flyers and broadsides 1873-1914, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 38-2)
  - Subseries H: General Materials 1865-1901
    - Virginia Democratic Convention 1889 (Box-folder 38-3)
    - Voter contact lists [1899], [2 folders; see also Radford Development Company deed book in Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 38-4)
    - Senatorial campaign notebook 1899 (Box-folder 38-5)
    - Notaries public and commissioners of deeds - city and county list 1901 (Box-folder 38-6)
    - Notaries public and commissioners of deeds - name list 1901 (Box-folder 38-7)
    - Political notes n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 38-8)
    - Miscellaneous 1865-1899 (Box-folder 38-9)
    - Miscellaneous n.d., [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 38-10)
- SERIES II: PERSONAL PAPERS 1860-1925
  - Subseries A: Presbyterian Church 1866-1924
    - Outgoing correspondence 1913, n.d. (Box-folder 38-11)
    - Incoming correspondence 1892-1924, n.d.
      - A-L (Box-folder 38-12-15)
      - M-Z, unidentified (Box-folder 39-1-5)
    - Church-related addresses and remarks n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 39-6)
    - Sunday school attendance record and minute book 1878-1896 (Box-folder 39-7)
    - Church treasurer's record 1909-1914 (Box-folder 39-8)
    - Printed materials, A-B (Box-folder 39-9)
      - Alliance of the Reformed Churches Throughout the World Holding the Presbyterian System, Reports submitted to the Sixth General Council, Glasgow1896
      - Burton, Ernest D. "Why I believe in praying" 1924
    - Printed materials, C-E (Box-folder 39-10)
      - "The Christian Observer's assault repelled" [1885?]
      - The Earnest worker June 1917
      - Executive Commission of the Alliance of the Reformed Churches, Western Section, Minutes
        - Sep 1892
        - Apr 1894
        - Oct 1894
        - Apr 1895
        - Oct 1895
      - Executive Committee of the Institute for Training Colored Ministers, Report1883
    - Printed materials, F (Box-folder 39-11)
      - "The First number of the Christian Observer (Supplement to the Christian Observer[1877?]
      - The Fundamentals: a testimony to the truth [19--?]
    - Printed materials, G-L (Box-folder 39-12)
      - General Assembly record, vol. 1, nos. 1-8 1883
      - General Presbyterian Council, "Report of the Ad Interim Committee" [1892]